Finding Aid for College of Architecture and Urban Planning (University of Michigan) student publications, 1924-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
College of Architecture and Urban Planning (University of Michigan) student publications 1924-1980 1930-1980
University of Michigan. College of Architecture and Urban Planning.
87120 Bimu C181 2
Student papers written for courses in architectural history research, mainly about Michigan architects, buildings and communities.
70 volumes in 3 boxes approximate
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by Emil Lorch (Donor # 4041 ) and the University of Michigan College of Architecture and Urban Planning (# 5805 )and the Art and Architecture Library ( #8439 ). Photographs and other visual materials appended to most student papers.
Periodic additions to the records expected.
Restricted access in part.
The CAUP student papers include restricted material in the following categories:
Student Academic Records -- Boxes 1-3
For a historical see the finding aid for A. Alfred Taubman College of Architecture + Urban Planning.
The records consist of student papers prepared for courses in the University of Michigan College of Architecture and Design (later Architecture and Urban Planning), primarily for classes in architectural history research; topics concern the architecture of specific Michigan communities, the architecture of historical buildings and homes, and studies of types of structures in Michigan; papers include historical description and appended visual material. Many of the papers include photos, postcards, and other illustrations relating to the architecture of specific Michigan communities, prominent historical buildings and houses in the state, and types of structures
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Church history.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Architects.; Architecture.; Dwellings--Michigan--Bay City.; City Hall (Detroit, Mich.); Conklin House (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Desenberg Building (Kalamazoo, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Detroit (Mich.)--Church history.; East Quadrangle (University of Michigan); Fenton (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; First Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.); Flint (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Flour-mills--Michigan--Geddes.; Flour-mills--Michigan--Saline.; Geddes (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Gogebic County (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Grand Rapids (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Harris Hall (University of Michigan); Horace H. Rackham School of Special Education.; Jenney, William Le Baron, 1832-1907.; Kalamazoo (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Lansing (Mich.); Lorch, Emil, 1870-1963.; Dwellings--Michigan--Marshall.; Mason, George D., b. 1856.; Medor Tromble House (Bay City, Mich.); Michigan Bell Telephone Company Building (Port Huron, Mich.); Miles-Sinclair House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Monroe (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Muehlig House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Nims House (Monroe, Mich.); North Campus (University of Michigan); Parker Mill (Geddes, Mich.); Pond, Irving K. (Irving Kane), 1857-1939.; Saarinen, Eero, 1910-1961.; Saarinen, Eliel, 1873-1950.; Saint Clair County (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Saline (Mich.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church buildings--Michigan--Saline.; Salvation Army.; Schlanderer House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Sheriff's House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Theaters--United States.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan. University Museum.; University of Michigan. Detroit Observatory.; Victor C. Vaughan House (University of Michigan); Walker Building (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Weller's Mill (Saline, Mich.); Dwellings--Michigan--Ypsilanti.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Buildings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Architecture.; Bay City (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Buildings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Buildings--Michigan--Detroit.; Buildings--Michigan--Fenton.; Buildings--Michigan--Flint.; Buildings--Michigan--Gogebic County.; Buildings--Michigan--Hartland.; Buildings--Michigan--Lansing.; Buildings--Michigan--Marshall.; Buildings--Michigan--Monroe.; Buildings--Michigan--Port Huron.; Buildings--Michigan--Saint Clair County.; Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Churches--Michigan--Detroit.; Churches--Michigan--Saline.; City and town halls--Michigan--Detroit.; City Hall (Detroit, Mich.); Conklin House (Ypsilanti, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Buildings.; Detroit (Mich.)--City and town halls.; Detroit (Mich.)--Government buildings.; Dining rooms.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Bay City.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ypsilanti.; East Quadrangle (University of Michigan); Fenton (Mich.)--Buildings.; Flint (Mich.)--Buildings.; First Methodist Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.); Gogebic County (Mich.)--Buildings.; Government buildings--Michigan--Detroit.; Harris Hall (University of Michigan); Hartland (Mich.)--Buildings.; Horace H. Rackham School of Special Education.; Lansing (Mich.)--Buildings.; Marshall (Mich.)--Buildings.; Miles-Sinclair House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Medor Tromble House (Bay City, Mich.); Michigan Bell Telephone Company Building (Bay City, Mich.); Muehlig House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Nims, Katherine Norman, 1875-1967.; Saline (Mich.)--Churches.; Salvation Army.; Schlanderer House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Sheriff's House (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Theaters--United States.; University of Michigan--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Campus.; University of Michigan. Detroit Observatory.; Victor C. Vaughan House (University of Michigan); Walker Building (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Ypsilanti (Mich.)--Buildings.; University of Michigan--Student housing.; Dormitories--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Student Papers
  [SR RESTRICTED for 75 years from date of creation under terms FERPA. Consult reference archivist for details.]
  - Anderson, Robert et al.
    - "Leesville 2" 1974 (group project) (Box 1)
  - Andrews, George F.
    - "Victor C. Vaughan House and East Quadrangle Men's Dormitories, University of Michigan" 1940 (Box 1)
  - Bajnai, Charles S.
    - "University of Michigan North Campus: Two Generations of Saarinens" 1977 (Box 1)
  - Barr, Louise Elizabeth
    - "Grand Rapids Architecture" 1925 (Box 1)
  - Beecher, Harold K.
    - "Architectural Development of the University of Michigan" 1935 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Francis (1935)
    - "The Churches of Ann Arbor" (Box 1)
  - Bery, George J.
    - "Industrial Architecture in Detroit" 1938 (Box 1)
  - Binda, Guido Stephen
    - "Architecture of Gogebic County" 1931 (Box 1)
  - Black, Kenneth C.
    - "An Architectural History of Lansing, Michigan" undated (Box 1)
  - Board, Leonard M. and Herbert J. Dunsmore
    - "A Study of the Flint Metropolitan Community Devoted to Environmental Health Functions, Responsibilities and Interests in Local Government" 1946 (Box 1)
  - Boehm, Benita
    - "American Architecture, Viewed by the Viennese" 1967 (Box 1)
  - Bostedor, Gerald C.
    - "One Hundred and Fifteen Years New [Sidney Smith house in Grass Lake]" 1950 (Box 1)
  - Brademas, T. Brooks
    - "An Evacuation Study of the Critical Target Area of Flint, Mich." 1955 (Box 1)
  - Brewer, Arthur W.
    - "1115 Woodlawn Ave., Ann Arbor" 1939 (Box 1)
  - Bryant, Dale
    - "The Computer and the Architectural Profession" 1968 (Box 1)
  - Bryant, Daniel C.
    - "Michigan Bell Telephone Company Building at Port Huron, Michigan" 1936 (Box 1)
  - Burket, Rhees E.
    - "Classical Revival Houses in and around Ann Arbor" 1925 (Box 1)
  - Burzinski, Joe and Craig Nicely
    - "The Old Detroit Observatory" 1980 (Box 1)
  - Cardona, Vic and Paul Ridley
    - "Second Walker Bldg., a Study in Restoration" 1976 (Box 1)
  - Chadwick, R. V.
    - "The Greek Revival in England and America: A House at 1116 Broadway, Ann Arbor, Michigan" 1938 (Box 1)
  - Chester, Timothy J.
    - "A Historical Analysis of the Selinsky-Green House As a First Step in Preservation" 1976 (Box 1)
  - Cripps, James.
    - "Mississauga City Hall" 1988 (Box 1)
  - Darling, J. Dale
    - "Irving Kane Pond, the Man, the Architect and the Author" circa 1930 (Box 1)
  - Daverman, J. T. (Box 2)
    - "The Schlanderer House. 504 South Main Street, Ann Arbor, Mich." 1937 (Box 2)
  - Diaz, Enrique
    (see Sarnecki, Christopher)
  - Duffy, R. Frances
    - "Das Amerikanshe Haus" 1971 (Box 2)
  - Dunsmore, Herbert J.
    (see Board, Leonard M.)
  - Eggebrecht, William M
    - "Greek-revival Architecture and the Muehlig Residence in Ann Arbor" undated (Box 2)
  - Gloster, Amos E.
    - "American Domestic Architecture During the Colonial and Greek Revival Periods [Hatch House, 721 Division, Ann Arbor, Mich.]" 1939 (Box 2)
  - Goodrich, Edward P.
    (see Von Blon, Helen)
  - Gordon, Charles A.
    - "The Work of G. W. Lloyd" 1940 (Box 2)
  - Gordon, Diane
    - "Hartland, Michigan: the Heartland of America" 1980 (Box 2)
  - Hafner, Genevieve
    - "The Old Architecture of Marshall, Michigan" 1935 (Box 2)
  - Harris, George K.
    - "The Detroit City Hall" 1939 (Box 2)
  - Itani, Fauzi
    - "Detroit Federal Buildings" 1932 (Box 2)
  - Jan, Moon-Lin
    - "The State Bank of Freiburg" 1988 (Box 2)
  - Kahn, Julius
    - "The Effect of the Social Environment on the Perception of the Architectural Environment" 1968 (Box 2)
  - Kelley, John R.
    - "The Greek Revival Influence in Michigan" 1928 (Box 2)
  - Kibbe, Gifford G.
    - "The Rackham School at Ypsilanti, Michigan" 1940 (Box 2)
  - King, Harry M.
    - "Koch House, Ann Arbor" 1941 (Box 2)
  - Krumm, Russell W.
    - "Chapin House, Ann Arbor" 1938 (Box 2)
  - Lahti, Ahde Kalervo
    - "Serigraphy: Photographic Silk Screen Printing Without Darkroom Facilities" 1968 (Box 2)
  - Lendrum, James T.
    - "The Architecture of the Methodist Episcopal Church" 1930 (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Stephen H.
    - "A New System for Producing Low Cost Housing" 1966 (Box 2)
  - Loheed, Phil
    - "Virginia Park" 1967 (Box 2)
  - Lorch, Elizabeth
    - "The City of Detroit" undated (Box 2)
  - McClure, James
    (see Mueting, Robert)
  - McKenny, Howard L.
    - "First Methodist Episcopal Church, Ann Arbor, Michigan" undated (Box 2)
  - McKie, Howard
    - "The Presbyterian Church, Saline, Michigan" 1940 (Box 2)
  - McKinley, Wessyl A.
    - "Architectural History Research on Fenton, Michigan" 1932 (Box 2)
  - Melniker, Albert
    - "The Sheriff's House, Ann Arbor, Michigan" 1940 (Box 2)
  - Meyer, Paul A.
  - Mitchell, Rowland J.
    - "Virginia Park Conservation Project" 1968 (Box 2)
  - Moffett, Paul B.
    - "Transition of Flint Architecture" 1940 (Box 2)
  - Moore, Charles L.
    - Differing Traits of Neo-Romanesque Building--A Comparison Between American and German Examples" 1970 (Box 2)
  - Morhous, Gwen C. (nd)
    - "The Conklin House [Ypsilanti, Mich.], an Example of the Greek Revival" (Box 2)
  - Mueting, Robert and James McClure
    - "A Preservation Study of Parker Mill [Geddes, Mich.]" 1977 (Box 2)
  - Nicely, Craig
    (see Burzinski, Joe)
  - O'Roke, Beth (Box 3)
    - "Salvation Army Architecture in Detroit and Ann Arbor" 1940 (Box 3)
  - Orman, Ben
    - "University of Michigan: the Development of the Central Quadrangle, a Survey of Buildings (1837-1907)" 1975 (Box 3)
  - Page, Stephen Spencer
    - "A History of American Cinema Architecture and a few Examples in Michigan" 1940 (Box 3)
  - Peterson, George L.
    - "Colonial Architecture in Ann Arbor" 1922 (Box 3)
  - Peterson, Roy Theodore
    - "Architect George D. Mason and his Works" 1929 (Box 3)
  - Raemdonck, Mark van
    - "Virginia Park Conservation Project" 1967 (Box 3)
  - Redstone, Lee
    - "New Towns in America" 1967 (Box 3)
  - Ridley, Paul
    (see Cardona, Vic)
  - Robinson, Richard M.
    - "Early Dwellings of Monroe: Monroe and its Early Architecture" 1936 (Box 3)
  - Roman, Roger C.
    - "Ann Arbor Model Cities: First Year Planning Phase" 1969 (Box 3)
  - Roman, Roger C.
    - "Student Architectural Advocacy" 1969 (Box 3)
  - Ross, Donald M.
    - "Some Old Architecture of St. Clair County, Michigan" 1926 (Box 3)
  - Ryder, Kevin P.
    - "The Nims Home: A Monroe Landmark" 1985 (Box 3)
  - Sarnecki, Christopher, Paul A. Meyer and Enrique Diaz
    - "Weller's Mill [Saline, Mich.]" 1976 (Box 3)
  - Schroeder, Douglas Frederick
    - "William Le Baron Jenney" 1958 (Box 3)
  - Schwenkmeyer, Carl Henry
    - "Churches of Detroit" 1924 (Box 3)
  - Smith, G. E. K.
    - "Mussolini's New Roman Forum" (Box 3)
  - Smith, Robert D.
    - "The Cooperative Planning of Space and Physical Facilities for Urban and Related Area Growth in Selected Michigan Communities: A Summary Report" 1968 (Box 3)
  - Stadler, James F.
    - "Early Colonial Architecture of Michigan" 1939 (Box 3)
  - Steere, Jean (1938)
    - "Sudworth House, Ann Arbor" (Box 3)
  - Telfer, J.
    (see Wargelin, P)
  - Urmston, Benton
    - "The Medor Tromble House, Bay City, Michigan" 1939 (Box 3)
  - Von Blon, Helen and Edward P. Goodrich
    - "The Haunted Tavern, formerly the Miles-Sinclair House, Ann Arbor, Michigan" 1938 (Box 3)
  - Vorel, Melvin W.
    - "The Detroit Metropolitan Superport" 1969 (Box 3)
  - Walzer, Donald M.
    - "Harris Hall of the University of Michigan" 1940 (Box 3)
  - Wargelin, P. and Telfer, J.
    - "Ann Arbor Central Business District--Campus Study" 1960 (Box 3)
  - Welter, Rudolf
    - "Toward Programmed Instructions for Problem Representation" 1971 (Box 3)
  - Williams, David S.
    - "The Desenberg Building, Adler and Sullivan [Kalamazoo, Mich.]" 1980 (Box 3)
  - Williams, Jack A.
    - "Gothic Churches in and Near Detroit" 1930 (Box 3)